翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
We can generalize this idea of keeping things simple, using the term invariant.
我们可以用“不变量”这个术语来概括这个简化事情的想法
So an invariant is simply a condition that is guaranteed to be true while your code is running,
不变量只是一个在你的代码运行时被保证为真的条件
assuming you haven't messed something up.
如果你没有搞砸什么的话
So it's the list of all the things that you can rely on-- all the truths.
这些是你可以依赖的所有事实
So an SLList with a sentinel node has at least the following invariants--
具有哨兵节点的 SLList 至少具有以下不变量
it has more, but here's a few that are kind of interesting.
其实有更多，但这几点很有趣
One is that the sentinel variable-- the sentinel reference--
一个是 sentinel 变量
it always points to a sentinel node.
它总是指向哨兵节点
That's something you have that's guaranteed to be true.
这是保证为真的
Another is that the first node in the list, if it exists, is always at sentinel.next.
另一种情况是 List 中的第一个节点（如果存在）总是位于 sentinel.next
And in fact, this is an invariant that I explicitly wrote out in the code right here as a comment.
事实上，这个不变量我在代码中作为注释显式地写出来了
Another one is that the size variable is always the total number of items that have been added, in this case.
另一点是 size 变量始终是已添加项的数量的总和
And so what invariants are good for
不变量的好处
is it make it easier to reason about your code.
是更容易对你的代码推理
You want to write a method that does something like, say, addLast?
你想要编写一个类似于 addLast 的方法吗？
Well, you know all of these facts.
你知道所有这些事实
So you know, for example, that addLast doesn't need to-- uh oh-- to worry now-- to worry.
比如 addLast 现在不需要...去担心
It don't have to worry about nulls--
它不必担心空值
a null value at first.
即 first 为 null
And it's also nice because it gives you a checklist of things you can think about,
还有一点好处是它给了你需要考虑的检查清单
that once your method is finished running,
一旦你的方法运行完毕
all your invariants should be true.
你所有的不变量都应该是真的
So for example, when we're trying to write addFirst,
例如，当我们尝试编写 addFirst 时
well, we need to-- if we keep all those invariants in mind,
我们需要把所有这些不变量都牢记在心
it might help avoid bugs like this, if we're-- if we have them listed on a sheet of paper or who knows what.
如果把它们列在一张纸上，可能有助于避免这样的 bug
Now, some programmers actually do like writing out the invariants, having them in the code,
一些程序员确实喜欢写出不变量，把它们放在代码中
maybe even explicitly stating them as comments throughout.
甚至可能从头到尾都明确地把它们写成注释
And sometimes you just think about them implicitly.
有时你只是隐约地想着它们
But I hope that you'll find the notion useful.
但我希望你会发现这个想法很有用
So that's it for today.
今天就到这里吧
In the next lecture, we're going to go even deeper.
在下一节课中，我们将更加深入
We're going to fix a couple of limitations of the SLList that we've come up with so far.
我们将解决目前为止提出的 SLList 的几个限制
For example, so far, we can only hold integers.
例如，到目前为止，我们只能保存整数
And if we look at addLast method, it's kind of slow.
而且 addLast 方法有点慢
So we're going to tackle those two problems next time,
所以我们下次要解决这两个问题
and then we'll talk a little bit about an alternate way to build lists, which is based on a raise.
然后稍微谈一谈建立链表的另一种方式
So I'll see you then,
到时见
and I hope you found this tour into the weird world of sentinel nodes to be fun.
我希望你觉得这次进入哨兵节点的奇怪世界的旅行很有趣
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）